Guide to the School of Art and Architecture, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
School of Art and Architecture, Yale University, records
1832-1996
RU 189
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
61.25
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, meeting minutes, statistics, financial records, and lecture materials documenting the students, faculty, curriculum, and general administration of the Yale School of Art and Architecture and its predecessors. Includes the records of Dean Everett V. Meeks.
Yale University. School of Art and Architecture
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 18-A (YRG 18-A), Central records and records of the dean of the Yale School of Art and Architecture and its predecessors.
Conditions Governing Access
While this collection as a whole is available for research, parts of it may be restricted due to law, university policy or fragility. Any restricted material will be noted as such.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
The study of visual arts at Yale began in 1832 with the opening of the Trumbull Gallery, the first college-affiliated art museum in the United States. In 1858, an exhibition in the Trumbull Gallery generated interest in establishing a formal course of study in the arts. With the support of Augustus Street (B.A. 1812), the School of Fine Arts (1869-1955) was established in 1866. It was formally opened in 1869 with the completion of Street Hall. The first bachelor of fine arts degree was conferred in 1891. Courses in architecture began in 1908; and the drama department (part of the school until 1955) was added in 1925. In 1928 the Yale Art Gallery opened. Louis Kahn designed the addition to the Yale Art Gallery which opened in 1953. From 1955 to 1958, the school was briefly renamed the School of Architecture and Design; from 1958 to 1972 it was named the School of Art and Architecture. In 1972, the two schools split and became the School of Art and the School of Architecture.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, meeting minutes, statistics, financial records, and lecture materials documenting the students, faculty, curriculum, and general administration of the Yale School of Art and Architecture and its predecessors. Includes the records of Dean Everett V. Meeks.
Architecture -- Study and teaching; Art schools; Art students; Art -- Study and teaching; College students; Schools of architecture; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Curricula; Universities and colleges -- Faculty; Meeks, Everett V. (Everett Victor), 1879-1954; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Art Gallery; Yale University. School of Architecture and Design; Yale University. School of Architecture; Yale University. School of Art and Architecture; Yale University. School of Art; Yale University. School of Fine Arts
- Records of the School of Art and Architecture, 1832-1969; Accession 1973-A-001
  Conditions Governing Access
  Materials in box 7, folder 49 are restricted until January 1, 2021 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - Minutes
    - Faculty minutes
      - 1872-1878 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 1878-1898 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - 1898-1910 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1910-1929 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 1930-1932 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Art Council, 1866-1887 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Art Council and Faculty, 1871-1876 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Archaeological Committee, 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and subject files
    - Admission: notes, 1873-1908 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Advertising, 1910-1918 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - American Association of Museums: New England Conference, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Appointments, resignations, deaths, 1872-1908 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - "Art and Art Schools": J. J. Chapman forty-eighth Anniversary Address, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Art Exhibition, first, 1867 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Art Exhibition: registration book, 1867 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Art 21b: assignments, notes, examinations, 1946-1965 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Awards and receptions, 1885-1910 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Blenner, Carle J.: exhibition cards, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Book catalogs, 1938-1947 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Chase, A. E., files: Art Gallery, 1966-1968, undated (Box 4, Folder 12 - 17)
    - Chase, A. E. files: Art Gallery, 1951-1966 (Box 5, Folder 18 - 23)
    - Chase, A. E. files: Art Gallery, 1935-1969 (Box 6, Folder 24 - 29)
    - English slides, list of, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Entry forms for the degree of Bachelor of Fine Arts, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Exhibition schedule and meeting, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - General Princtpals of Drawing, Art elective for juniors, Art I: notes, 1911-1912 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Griggs, Maitland, F., 1936-1940 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Modern Architecture notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - "Needs of the University suggested by the Faculties", 1871 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Pamphlets, 18th century: Art 33, undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Pamphlets and clippings: Flemish and Dutch, undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Parke, N. Ross, 1925-1940 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Poems: 1864 and Shady Side Academy 50th Anniversary poem, 1864, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - President's Report: loose pages from booklet, 1913-1916 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Prints and clippings: French and Spanish, undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Prints and clippings: Italian, undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Resumes: miscellaneous, 1904-1915, undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Sketch book: Langzettel, G. H., 1888-1889 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Still-Life Painting Class report, 1909-1910 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Student grade reports, 1922-1924 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Student sketches and grades, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 49)
      Materials in this folder are restricted until Jan 1, 2021 due to University policy set by the Yale Corporation.
    - Trumbull Gallery
      - Admissions book, 1832-1863 (Box 8, Folder 50)
      - Bills and receipt record, 1832-1862 (Box 8, Folder 51)
      - "The Trumbull Gallery" by J. H. Morgan: galley proofs, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 52)
      - Visitor's registery, 1866-1867 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Walters Art Gallery, 1936-1937 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Departmental
      - 1901 (Box 10, Folder 55)
      - 1901-1912 (Box 10, Folder 56)
      - 1907-1915 (Box 10, Folder 57)
      - 1907-1941 (Box 10, Folder 58)
      - 1913-1914 (Box 10, Folder 59 - 62)
      - 1913-1916 (Box 10, Folder 63)
      - 1913-1922 (Box 10, Folder 64 - 65)
      - 1914-1915 (Box 11, Folder 66)
      - 1914-1919 (Box 11, Folder 67)
      - 1914-1922 (Box 11, Folder 68)
      - 1914-1939 (Box 11, Folder 69)
      - 1915 (Box 11, Folder 70 - 71)
      - 1915-1923 (Box 11, Folder 72)
      - 1916-1919 (Box 11, Folder 73)
      - 1917 (Box 11, Folder 74 - 75)
      - 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 76)
      - 1917-1919 (Box 12, Folder 77 - 78)
      - 1918-1920 (Box 12, Folder 79)
      - 1919 (Box 12, Folder 80)
      - 1919-1921 (Box 12, Folder 81)
      - 1920-1922 (Box 12, Folder 82)
      - 1922-1923 (Box 12, Folder 83)
      - 1922-1944 (Box 12, Folder 84)
      - 1923-1927 (Box 12, Folder 85)
      - 1934-1936 (Box 12, Folder 86)
      - 1937-1942 (Box 12, Folder 87)
      - 1938 (Box 12, Folder 88)
      - 1956 (Box 12, Folder 89)
    - Lectures
      - Lists, 1871-1911 (Box 13, Folder 90)
      - Day, Frank Miles: "Civic Improvement in the United States", 1907 (Box 13, Folder 91)
      - Meeks, Everett V., 1925 (Box 13, Folder 92)
      - Roosval, Johnny, 1927-1935 (Box 13, Folder 93)
      - Proposed, 1929-1930 (Box 13, Folder 94)
      - Trowbridge Lectures, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 95)
      - Schulumberger, D.M.: "Palmyra and it's Temples", 1930 (Box 13, Folder 96)
      - Proposed, 1930-1931 (Box 13, Folder 97)
      - Cousins, James A., 1930 (Box 13, Folder 98)
      - Averardi, Franco Brono, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 99)
      - Faculty, 1930-1931 (Box 13, Folder 100)
      - Trowbridge Lectures, 1930-1931 (Box 13, Folder 101)
      - Publicity, 1930-1939 (Box 13, Folder 102)
      - Bonner, Campbell, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 103)
      - Ingholt, Harold: on Palmyra, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 104)
      - Nag, Kalidas, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 105)
      - Riefstahl, Rudolph, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 106)
      - Pijoan, Joseph, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 107)
      - Phillips, Duncan, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 108)
      - Musical Department, 1931-1932 (Box 13, Folder 109)
      - Faculty and museum staff, 1931-1932 (Box 13, Folder 110)
      - Ashbee, C.R., 1931 (Box 13, Folder 111)
      - Declos, Auguste, 1931-1933 (Box 13, Folder 112)
      - Von Hindenberg, Baroness, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 113)
      - Boucher, Francois M., 1932 (Box 14, Folder 114)
      - Capart, Jean, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 115)
      - Fleury, Comte Serge, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 116)
      - La Farge, C. Grant, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 117)
      - McKenzi, R. Tait, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 118)
      - Miller, Alec, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 119)
      - Pope, Arthur Upham, 1932-1934 (Box 14, Folder 120)
      - Salmony, Alfred, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 121)
      - Public Lecture Course, 1932-1933 (Box 14, Folder 122)
      - Classical Department, 1923-1933 (Box 14, Folder 123)
      - Aubert, Marcel, 1934-1936 (Box 14, Folder 124)
      - Focillon, Henri, 1933-1938 (Box 14, Folder 125)
      - Binyon, Lawrence, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 126)
      - Coomaraswamy, A. K., 1933 (Box 14, Folder 127)
      - Milliken, William Mathewson, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 128)
      - Ranke, Herman, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 129)
      - Taft, Lorado, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 130)
      - Watkins, C. Law, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 131)
      - Glueck, Nelson, 1933-1934 (Box 14, Folder 132)
      - Trowbridge Lectures, 1933-1934 (Box 14, Folder 133)
      - Magonigle, H. Van Bruen, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 134)
      - Ostberg, Ragner, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 135)
      - Panofsky, Erwin, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 136)
      - Ward, Clarence, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 137)
      - Casson, Stanley, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 138)
      - Tietze, Hans, 1934-1935 (Box 14, Folder 139)
      - Trowbridge Lectures, 1934-1935 (Box 14, Folder 140)
      - Bull Ludlow, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 141)
      - Kinney, Troy, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 142)
      - Pauli, Gustav, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 143)
      - Movies, radio, 1933-1935 (Box 14, Folder 144)
      - Trowbridge Lectures, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 145)
      - Offered, lectures, 1935-1936 (Box 15, Folder 146)
      - Ryerson Lectures, 1935-1936 (Box 15, Folder 147)
      - Barry, Philip; Brown, John Mason, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 148)
      - Wace, A. J. B., 1936-1939 (Box 15, Folder 149)
      - Clark, Kenneth, 1936-1937 (Box 15, Folder 150)
      - Grainger, Alfred H., 1936-1937 (Box 15, Folder 151)
      - Offered, lectures, 1936-1937 (Box 15, Folder 152)
      - Van Kuyck, Hugo, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 153)
      - Clarke, Gimore D., 1937 (Box 15, Folder 154)
      - Farrand, Beatrix, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 155)
      - Foss Art Museum, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 156)
      - Offered, lectures, 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 157)
      - Richter, Gisela, 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 158)
      - Asplund, Gunnar, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 159)
      - Huth, Hans, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 160)
      - Leger, Ferdinand, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 161)
      - Sandberg-Valvala, Evelyn, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 162)
      - Sterling-Fouquet-Cezanne (cancelled), 1938 (Box 16, Folder 163)
      - VanKuyck, Hugo, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 164)
      - Museum, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 165)
      - Proposed, 1938-1939 (Box 16, Folder 166)
      - Ackerman, Phyllis, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 167)
      - Alvar, Aalto, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 168)
      - Boethius, Axel, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 169)
      - Codrington, de B. Kenneth, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 170)
      - Ganz, Paul, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 171)
      - Kranz, Heinrich B., 1939 (Box 16, Folder 172)
      - Ozenfant, Amedee, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 173)
      - Rawlings, F. Ian, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 174)
      - Rubenstein, Lewis, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 175)
      - Siren, Osvald, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 176)
      - Sterling, Charles M., 1939 (Box 16, Folder 177)
      - Van Puyvelde, Leo, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 178)
      - Yale Dame, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 179)
      - Proposed, 1939-1941 (Box 16, Folder 180)
      - Delivered, 1940-1941 (Box 17, Folder 181)
      - Ryerson Lectureship Fund, 1940-1947 (Box 17, Folder 182)
      - Lectures proposed, 1940-1952 (Box 17, Folder 183 - 184)
      - Delivered, 1941-1942 (Box 17, Folder 185)
      - Proposed, 1942-1944 (Box 17, Folder 186 - 187)
      - Delivered, 1943-1944 (Box 17, Folder 188)
      - Proposed, 1944-1945 (Box 17, Folder 189)
      - Italian, 1945-1946 (Box 17, Folder 190)
      - Proposed, 1945-1946 (Box 17, Folder 191)
      - Burke, Joseph, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 192)
      - Proposed, 1946-1947 (Box 17, Folder 193)
      - Art Gallery, 1933-1950 (Box 18, Folder 194 - 201)
      - Art Gallery, 1952-1964 (Box 19, Folder 202 - 208)
  - Financial records
    - Account Books
      - 1868-1906 (Box 20, Folder 1 - 2)
      - 1906-15 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - 1914-16 (Box 20, Folder 4 - 5)
    - Treasurer's Books
      - 1868-1903 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - 1869-1914 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - 1872-1917 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - 1918-22 (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - 1923-25 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - 1925-27 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - 1927-28 (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - 1928-29 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - 1930-1932 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - Bills and receipts: miscellaneous, 1896-1913 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Street Hall Addition
      - Bills and receipts:construction, 1864-1911 (Box 27, Folder 16 - 21)
      - Correspondence, 1909-1911 (Box 27, Folder 22)
      - Notes, 1909 (Box 27, Folder 23)
      - Specifications, 1909 (Box 27, Folder 24)
      - Speeches on construction: E. E. Salisbury, undated (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Roll books (daily attendance)
    - 1913-1919 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - 1919-1931 (Box 29, Folder 2 - 8)
    - 1931-1938 (Box 30, Folder 9 - 15)
  - Printed matter
    - Newspaper and magazine clippings: exhibitions, lectures and awards, 1908-1955 (Box 31, Folder 1 - 2)
    - Miscellaneous: notes, photographs and memoranda of other museums, pamphlets, publications, 1904-1952, undated (Box 31, Folder 3 - 5)
- Records of the School of the Fine Arts, 1929-1959; Accession 1978-A-001
  The materials are open for research.
  - Architectural Forum, 1947, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aubert, Professor Marcel: Art 51-52, correspondence, 1941-1944 (Box 1, Folder 2 - 3)
  - Aubert, Professor Marcel, and Focillon, Professor Henri: Applications for assistantships, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Aubert, Professor Marcel and Focillon, Professor Henri: Art 51-52, History of Art in the Middle Ages, 1932-1940 (Box 1, Folder 5 - 8)
  - Corporation Committee on Libraries and Museums, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dealers, 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 10 - 13)
  - Exhibitions, 1929-1930, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Focillon, Professor Henri: see Aubert, Professor Marcel, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Library Committee, 1930-1937 (Box 2, Folder 16 - 19)
  - New Haven Historical Society, 1930-1933 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Public Works of Art, 1933-1937 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Publicity, 1938-1943 (Box 2, Folder 22 - 23)
  - Seymour, President Charles, 1936-1943 (Box 2, Folder 24 - 27)
  - Street Hall floor plans: Army agreement, 1942-1945, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Time Magazine, 1959 February 23 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Motion picture film of a lecture given by Walker Evans, circa 1971; Accession 1980-A-001
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - Evans in Art Gallery (no sound, 700'), circa 1971; 1 (Box 1)
    - Use copy (syncronized audio and video), 1 (Box 1U)
  - Sound track (800'), circa 1971; 1 (Box 2)
- Records and historical statistics, 1864-1945; Accession 1987-A-049
  - Statistics and Background Information, 1864-1945
    - Introduction, 1864-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - History, 1864-1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Dates of First Degrees, 1864-1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Rome Prize Winners, 1864-1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Travelling Fellowship Winners, 1864-1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Enrollment and Degree Figures, 1864-1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Graduates and Certificate Holders, 1864-1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Scholarships and Prizes, 1864-1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Exams, 1864-1945 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Elections, 1864-1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Regarding Quality Credits, 1864-1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Inter-Department Charges, 1864-1945 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Collegiate Schools of Architecture, 1864-1945 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Minutes: Meetings of the Committee on Architectural Planning, Yale University
    - 1919 Nov 14 - 1921 Feb 11 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1921 Mar 11 -1923 Dec 7 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1924 Jan 11 - 1924 Nov 7 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1924 Dec 12 -1926 Jun 13 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - The Iktinos Society, 1928-1932 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Records of Charles Sawyer, circa 1947-1982; Accession 1991-A-007
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2018
  Scope and Contents
  Charles Henry Sawyer was Professor of the History of Art at Yale, 1947-1957; Dean of the School of Fine Arts, 1947-1955; Dean of the School of Architecture and Design, 1955-1956; and Director of the Division of Arts, 1947-1955.
  - Proposed Art Department Changes: Correspondence, 1947-1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Division of the Arts: Committee Reports, 1947-1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Corporation: Educational Policy Committee, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual Reports to the President, 1948-1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Division of the Arts: Articles, 1948-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Department of Architecture: Departmental Problems, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Tour of Art Departments in New York State schools, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - History of Art 51: Syllabus, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Art History: Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Sawyer, Charles: Personal Correspondence, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition: "Graduate Photography at Yale", 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Alumni Newsletters, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bulletin of Yale University: School of Art, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Art Journal", 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Financial Aid Picture, Graphic Design, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Graphic Design Program: Directory, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Article: "Kahn and Yale", undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Timothy Dwight College (Charles Sawyer, Master): Reports to the President, 1949-1953 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Timothy Dwight College: Directory, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Records of the dean, 1945-1968; Accession 1996-A-018
  - Advice Letters, Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Admissions, Board of, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alumni Board, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alumni Board, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alumni Board Trip, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alumni Correspondence, Dean, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alumni Day, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alumni Day, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alumni Day, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alumni Fund, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Institute of Architects, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Applicants for Positions, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Department of Architecture, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Department of Art, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Arts Festival, New Haven, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Art Gallery, General, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Art Gallery, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Automobile Conference, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Automobile Permits, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - A - Miscellaneous, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Birnie, James (Reynolds Metals), Correspondence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - B -Miscellaneous, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - City Planning, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - City Planning, Budget, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - City Planning and Candidates, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, (Danes-Smith), 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence (Osborn), 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence (Sawyer-Smith), 1955 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - C - Miscellaneous, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Drama School, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - D -Miscellaneous, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Exhibition and Lecture Committee, 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - E -Miscellaneous
  - Faculty and Staff Lists, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Fellowships, Info Applications (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - "Friendly Letters", 1955 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Fulbright Committee, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - F- Miscellaneous, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - F- Miscellaneous, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - General Motors Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Graduate School, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Graphic Design, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - G -Miscellaneous, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Heraldry, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - History of Art, General, 1947-1950 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - History of Art, 1955-1960 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1945-1953 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Hospital Proposals, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Hopper, Magnus T. Fellowship, 1952-1961 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Howland, Harry E. Memorial award, 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - H -Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - H -Miscellaneous, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - State University of Iowa Correspondence, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - I -Miscellaneous, 1946-1961 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - J -Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - K- Miscellaneous, 1947-1959 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Lecture Committee, 1947-1959 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Lectures, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Phillips, John Marshall Fellowship, Acknowledgments for Contributions, 1952-1954 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Phillips, John Marshall, Article in Associates' Bulletin, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Phillips, John Marshall, Correspondence with Harvard Press, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Phillips, John Marshall, Correspondence Regarding Death, 1952-1954 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Phillips, John Marshall Fellowship, General Correspondence, 1952-1954 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Library, Art, Slide and photo Collection, 1957-1960 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Library, School of Fine Arts, 1947-1950 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Library and Museum Council, 1947-1950 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Life Magazine Symposium, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - L -Miscellaneous, 1947-1961 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Modern Art, Intrinsic interest in, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - M -Miscellaneous, 1947-1961 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - M -Miscellaneous, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - National Architecture Accrediting Board, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Navy R.O.T.C., 1947-1950 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - News Bureau, 1947-1950 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Weekly Newsletter, 1947-1961 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Monthly Announcement, 1947-1950 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Norfolk Summer School, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - N -Miscellaneous, 1947-1961 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Osborn, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - O -Miscellaneous, 1947-1961 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Painting Department, General, 1947-1950 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Personnel Director's Office, 1947-1960 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Perspecta Magazine, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 87)